shotatlife.org 2019-02-21

# Privacy Policy - Shot@Life : Shot@Life

### The UN Foundation is committed to the privacy of those individuals who visit and interact with [www.unfoundation.org](http://www.unfoundation.org/) and [www.shotatlife.org](http://www.shotatlife.org/). This Privacy Policy is meant to help you understand what information we collect, why we collect it, and how you can update, retrieve and request removal of your information.

—

By visiting our Website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website.

Please note that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our Website and other [websites owned and managed by the UN Foundation](http://www.unfoundation.org/what-we-do/campaigns-and-initiatives/). They do not apply to information that you may submit to us offline or to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link.

The UN Foundation is the sole owner of the information collected on the Website. We do not share your personal information with companies, organizations, or individuals outside of the Foundation.

Generally, you are free to visit the UN Foundation Website without submitting data that identifies you personally. However, we do ask you to provide some personal data for certain interactions within our Website. This data varies depending on the interaction, but may include name, address, email address, and other similar information (“Personal Information”). We do not request sensitive information such as social security numbers. If you make a donation online we do ask for your credit card number – but we do not store card numbers.

**Cookies**

Like many websites, we use “cookies,” which are small text files that are stored on your computer or equipment when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences. We use cookies to track use of our Websites and online services. We may also use cookies to monitor traffic, improve the Websites, and make it easier and/or relevant for your use. This Website is functional without the retention of cookies. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies.

Below are the ways in which we collect your Personal Information through specific actions and circumstances.  
**By choosing to participate in any of the following activities, you consent to our collection and use of your Personal Information.**

  * When you register for an account on the UN Foundation website or any UN Foundation campaign website;
  * When you sign up to receive email newsletters from us;
  * When you participate in surveys;
  * When you complete an advocacy activity or survey online;
  * When you submit a donation online;
  * When you register for and participate in our programs, activities, initiatives, and events;
  * When you request information or assistance;
  * In conjunction with processing your grant applications;
  * In conjunction with your employment inquiries or applications;
  * When you participate with social media and peer to peer accounts involving UN Foundation;
  * When you participate in online communities;
  * In conjunction with any verification of your account information;
  * In conjunction with investigations into any activity that may violate the law or the website’s terms and conditions;
  * When you communicate with us through the website;
  * When you provide user-generated content on any part of the website that permits it; and
  * In conjunction with any other place on the website where you knowingly volunteer personal information; and
  * When you send us a donation by check or wire.

In addition, when you interact with the Website, our servers may keep an activity log that does not identify you individually (“Non-Personal Information”). Generally, we collect the following categories of Non-Personal Information:

  * We may collect certain demographic data such as age, gender, and five-digit zip code as part of collecting personal information;
  * We collect and store certain device information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to access the Website. This information may include IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information;
  * We automatically log certain usage information about your use of the Website. This information includes a reading history of the pages you view. We use this information to provide you with a more customized experience on the Website;
  * We collect and store additional “traffic data” such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports, session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses; and
  * We collect and store your search terms and search results.

**Social media platforms**

When you interact with any UN Foundation page or account on a social media platform, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, LinkedIn, Instagram, YouTube, Medium, Exposure or Pinterest we may also collect the personal information that you make publicly available to us on that page or through that account, including your account ID or “handle.” Please be advised that each social media platform may collect specific data not listed here, and the UN Foundation has no control over how third-party platforms collect or use your personal information. Please refer to that platform’s privacy policy for additional guidance.

We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Website. With your consent we may use your Personal and Non-Personal Information in the following ways:

**General Uses**

  * For editorial purposes;
  * Responding to your inquiries;
  * Communicating with you about your account or transactions (including donations) with us and sending you information about features on our Website or about the Foundation;
  * Communicating with you about changes to our policies;
  * Sending you newsletters, mailings, and information about programs, initiatives, activities, and events by e-mail or another medium;
  * Processing your employment application;
  * Event or program registration;
  * Optimizing or improving our programs, services, and operations;
  * Research and development;
  * Detecting, investigating, and preventing activities that may violate our policies or be illegal;
  * Advocating to decision makers on specific issues;
  * Performing statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Website and their usage patterns; and
  * Managing our organization.

The United Nations Foundation intends to protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information. We have implemented appropriate physical, technical, and organizational measures, including industry-standard encryption for transmission of credit card information, to help keep your information secure, accurate, current and complete.

If you have any concerns about the security and confidentiality of your Personal Information, please contact [action@unfoundation.org](mailto:action@unfoundation.org).

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679 is a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy for all individuals within the European Union. It also addresses the export of personal data outside the EU.

We will use reasonable efforts to securely process all personal information in line with the rights specified under the GDPR, in particular, those related to the following requests:

  * Access to your Personal Information;
  * Correction of the Personal Information we hold;
  * Deletion of your Personal Information;
  * A restriction of processing of your Personal Information;
  * Transfer of your Personal Information to another party; or,
  * Objection to processing of your Personal Information based on the UN Foundation’s legitimate interests (or those of a third party) to use it.

Please send an email to [action@unfoundation.org](mailto:action@unfoundation.org) if any of the following apply:

  * You have any questions or requests regarding this policy;
  * You would like to remove all Personal Information from our database;
  * You would like to view Personal Information you shared with us;
  * You would like to change your account preferences;
  * You no longer wish to receive email updates from the UN Foundation;
  * You believe the UN Foundation has erroneous or incomplete information about you; or,
  * You believe a child below the age of 16 years may have submitted Personal Information without the consent of a parent or guardian.

For more information about your rights under the GDPR, please visit <https://gdpr-info.eu/>.

If the UN Foundation decides to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this page so you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner.

Your continued use of our Website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept those changes. Our most up-to-date privacy policy will always be available here.

Questions and comments should be directed to [action@unfoundation.org](mailto:action@unfoundation.org).

**Email Scams**

Several deceptive emails claiming to be from or associated with the United Nations Foundation, Kathy Calvin, Rick Parnell, Ted Turner, and Timothy Wirth are circulating on the Internet. These emails often include our logo, photos, links, or other information from our Web site.

Some emails claim the recipient has won a lottery or other prize and request detailed personal information or a payment of some kind in order to receive the winnings. Some mention other foundations and organizations based in London and the United Kingdom none of which are a part of these scams. Other emails direct recipients to Web sites that promise large returns on investments and claim a portion of returns will be donated to the foundation.

The sources and contents of these emails, websites, and accompanying materials are in no way associated with the United Nations Foundation, Mr. Turner or Mr. Wirth. For your own protection, we strongly recommend not responding to emails making such claims.

The UN Foundation has reported, and will continue to report, these deceptive spam emails to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Internet Crime Complaint Center (IC3) and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI). For more information about the FTC’s efforts against deceptive spam, please visit [www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/spam/report.html](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/spam/report.html). For more information about the IC3, please visit [www.ic3.gov/](http://www.ic3.gov/) . For information on the FBI, please visit [www.fbi.gov/](http://www.fbi.gov/), or contact your local FBI office.

You can also email your inquiries about scam email, letters, and phone calls to [action@unfoundation.org](mailto:action@unfoundation.org).
